A Guide to the Records of Governor Kaine's Office of Community Integration for People with Disabilities, 2002-2009
Library of Virginia
- Series V. Olmstead Task Force Recommendations, 2004-2005., Extent: 5 boxes (1.75 cubic feet). (Box 15-19)
  Olmstead Task Force Recommendations, 2004-2005, are housed in 5 boxes and are arranged by recommendation number. The Community Integration Implementation Team was charged with cost out and updates to the 201 recommendations in One Community, the Report of the Olmstead Task Force; indentifying and implementing recommendations that could be implemented administratively within each agency; indentifying recommendations that would require new resources within each agency's budget; prioritizing the timing with which those recommendations would be requested to be implemented; preparing budget proposals for the Governor's consideration; identifying recommendations that would require regulatory changes and overseeing the process for adoption of regulations; identifying all recommendations that would require action outside an agencies' authority and recommending to the Governor a process for implementation; seeking advice from the Community Integration Oversight Advisory Committee; and reporting annually to the Committee on the activities of the Team and status of the Olmstead decision with the Commonwealth. The Team divided the 201 recommendations in the Task Force Report into five categories for the purpose of costing them out - recommendations for responsible agencies; recommendations for assignment of a lead agency when needed; recommendations for multiple agencies; recommendations that appeared to be outside the authority or responsibility of agencies represented on the Team; and recommendations that had already been fully implemented by January 2004. Due to the volume of recommendations and the time frame involved, recommendations were divided into two cost out phases: Phase 1 (2004) and Phase II (2005). Recommendations fall into categories for Consumer Choice of and Access to Needed Services and Supports; Consumer and Family Involvement; Consumer Rights; Health and Safety; Educating Consumers, Family Members and Providers; Educating the Public; Employment; Housing; Research and Knowledge; Transportation; Workforce and Qualifications of Providers; and Olmstead Planning and Implementation. Most of the recommendation files include Olmstead Task Force Recommendation Cost Out Reports which identify lead agency name and contact, time frame, impact, assumptions and requirements of the recommendation. May also include correspondence, agendas, fiscal impact statements, legislation, presentations, and other reports.
  - Recommendation #1, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Recommendation #2, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Recommendation #3, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Recommendation #4, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Recommendation #5, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Recommendation #6, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Recommendation #7 and #180, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Recommendation #8, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Recommendation #9, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Recommendation #10, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Recommendation #12 and #192, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Recommendation #13, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Recommendation #14, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Recommendation #15, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Recommendation #16, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Recommendation #17 (merged with #7 and #180), 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Recommendation #19, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Recommendation #20, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Recommendation #21, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Recommendation #23, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Recommendation #24, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Recommendation #26 and #170, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Recommendation #27, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Recommendation #28, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Recommendation #29, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Recommendation #30, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Recommendation #31a, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Recommendation #31b, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Recommendation #32, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Recommendation #33, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Recommendation #34 and #58, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Recommendation #35, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Recommendation #36, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Recommendation #38, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Recommendation #39, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Recommendation #40, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Recommendation #41, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Recommendation #42, #121, #122, #123, #166 and #186 (merged), 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Recommendation #43, 2004-2005. (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Recommendation #44, 2004-2005. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Recommendation #45, 2004-2005. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Recommendation #46, 2004-2005. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Recommendation #47, 2004-2005. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Recommendation #48, 2004-2005. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Recommendation #49, 2004-2005. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Recommendation #50, 2004-2005. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Recommendation #51, 2004-2005. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Recommendation #52, 2004-2005. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Recommendation #53, 2004-2005. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Recommendation #54, 2004-2005. (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Recommendation #56, 2004-2005. (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Recommendation #57, 2004-2005. (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Recommendation #58, 2004-2005. (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Recommendation #59, 2004-2005. (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Recommendation #60, 2004-2005. (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Recommendation #61, 2004-2005. (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Recommendation #62, 2004-2005. (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Recommendation #63, 2004-2005. (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Recommendation #65, 2004-2005. (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Recommendation #66, 2004-2005. (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Recommendation #68, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Recommendation #67, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Recommendation #69 and 137, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Recommendation #70, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Recommendation #72, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Recommendation #73, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Recommendation #74 and 75, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Recommendation #76 and 142, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Recommendation #79, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Recommendation #80, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Recommendation #81, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Recommendation #82, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Recommendation #83, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Recommendation #86, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Recommendation #87, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Recommendation #88, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Recommendation #89, 149 and 189, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Recommendation #90, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Recommendation #91, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Recommendation #93, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Recommendation #94, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Recommendation #95, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Recommendation #96, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Recommendation #97, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Recommendation #98, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Recommendation #99, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Recommendation #100, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Recommendation #101, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Recommendation #102, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Recommendation #103, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Recommendation #104, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Recommendation #105, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Recommendation #106, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Recommendation #107, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Recommendation #108, 2004-2005. (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - Recommendation #109, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Recommendation #110a and 110b, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Recommendation #111, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Recommendation #112, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Recommendation #113, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Recommendation #114, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Recommendation #115, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Recommendation #116a, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Recommendation #116b, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Recommendation #117, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Recommendation #118, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Recommendation #119, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Recommendation #120, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Recommendation #124, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Recommendation #125, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Recommendation #126, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Recommendation #127, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Recommendation #128, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Recommendation #129, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Recommendation #130, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Recommendation #131, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Recommendation #132, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Recommendation #133, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Recommendation #134, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Recommendation #135, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Recommendation #136, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Recommendation #137, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Recommendation #138, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Recommendation #139, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Recommendation #141, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Recommendation #142, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Recommendation #143, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Recommendation #144, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Recommendation #145, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Recommendation #146, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Recommendation #147a, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Recommendation #147b, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Recommendation #148, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - Recommendation #149, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - Recommendation #150, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - Recommendation #151, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 41)
  - Recommendation #152, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 42)
  - Recommendation #154, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 43)
  - Recommendation #155, 2004-2005. (Box 18, Folder 44)
  - Recommendation #156, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Recommendation #157, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Recommendation #158, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Recommendation #159, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Recommendation #160, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Recommendation #162, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Recommendation #163, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Recommendation #164, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Recommendation #165, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Recommendation #167, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Recommendation #169, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Recommendation #170, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Recommendation #171, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Recommendation #172, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Recommendation #173, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Recommendation #174, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Recommendation #175, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Recommendation #176, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Recommendation #177, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Recommendation #179, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Recommendation #180, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Recommendation #181, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Recommendation #182, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Recommendation #183, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Recommendation #184, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Recommendation #185, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Recommendation #187, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Recommendation #188, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Recommendation #189, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Recommendation #190, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Recommendation #191, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Recommendation #192, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Recommendation #195, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Recommendation #197, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Recommendation #198, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Recommendation #199, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Recommendation #200, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Recommendation #201, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Recommendation #202, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Recommendation #206, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - Recommendation #207, 2004-2005. (Box 19, Folder 41)
- Series VI. Reports, 2004-2005., Extent: 1 box (.35 cubic feet). (Box 20)
  Reports, 2004-2005, are housed in 1 box and are arranged chronologically. Includes Annual Reports of the Community Integration Implementation Team (First and Second) and the Community Integration Oversight Advisory Committee (First and Second), as well as drafts of these reports, and other status reports.
  - First Annual Report of the Community Integration Implementation Team to the Community Integration Oversight Advisory Committee, 2004 July 15. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Olmstead Implementation Team Dedicated Revenue Stream Report, 2004 July. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - First Annual Report of the Community Integration Oversight Advisory Committee to Governor Warner, 2004 Oct 19. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Implementation Status Report, 2004. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Olmstead Initiative Quarterly Reports to the Governor from the Director of the Office of Community Integration for People with Disabilities, 2004. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Second Annual Report of the Community Integration Implementation Team to the Community Integration Oversight Advisory Committee, 2005 July 15. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Second Annual Report of the Community Integration Oversight Advisory Committee to Governor Warner, 2005 Oct 3. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Drafts - First Annual Report of the Community Integration Implementation Team, 2004. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Drafts - First Annual Report of the Community Integration Oversight Advisory Committee, 2004. (Box 20)
  - Drafts - Second Annual Report of the Community Integration Implementation Team, 2005. (Box 20, Folder 8)